A Guide to the James Branch Cabell Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7779-c
James Branch Cabell Collection 1918-1954
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7779-c
ca. 54 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1968 Mar 1
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Jun 1; TLS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1918 Jun 15; TLS, 5 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Jan 13; TLS, 3 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1919 May 2; TLS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1919 May 17; ALS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Jun 20; TLS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Oct 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Nov 5; TLS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1919 Dec 22; TLS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1920 Jan 19; TLS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1920 Jun 15; TLS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1920 Aug 16; TLS, 4 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1920 Oct 12; TLS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1920 Nov 23; TLS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Apr 24; ALS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1921 May 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Oct 18; TLS, 4 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Oct 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Nov 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Nov 7; TLS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Nov 14; ALS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Dec 16; ALS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Jan 5; TLS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Jul 1; TLS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Jun 23; TLS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Oct 25; TLS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Dec 31; TLS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Aug 8; ALS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Nov 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Sep 27; TLS, 3 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1929 Sep 12; TLS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1929 Nov 22; Telegram
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, [1930]; TLS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1932 May 2; ALS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1933 Jul 25; TLS, 3 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1934 Dec 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1942 Jan 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1943 May; ALS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1946 Oct 8; ALS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1947 Jun [4]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1949 Apr 20; ALS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1949 Apr 21; APCS
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1949 Dec 21; ALS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1950 Nov 4; ALS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1951 Apr 30; ALS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1952 Feb [4]; ALS, 2 p.
  - Dorothy Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1954 Apr 25; Telegram
  - Dorothy Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, n.d.; ALS, 3 p.
- Miscellaneous
  - Obituaries of Joseph Hergesheimer, 1954 Apr 27; 2 clippings
- Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook A, 1927-1928; 86 p.
    Clippings, re:
    Something About Eve
    Frances Newman
  - Scrapbook B, 1916-1923; 98 p.
    Jurgen
    and Gallantry, with letters as follows
  - Letters in Scrapbook B
    - P. A. Carmichael to James Branch Cabell, [1922] Aug 8; ALS, 2 p.
    - Ryan Walker to James Branch Cabell, encl. a drawing for Jurgen, 1922 Jul 17; ALS, 1 p.
    - Charles Ridgely to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Aug 30; TLS, 1 p.
    - Norman Fitts to James Branch Cabell, [1922]; ALS, 2 p.
    - Lewis Galantiere to James Branch Cabell, 1922 May 9; ALS, 2 p.
    - Aleister Crowley to James Branch Cabell, 1922 May 25; TLS, 2 p.
    - Franz Blei to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Jun 20; TLS, 1 p.
    - Edwin Bjorkman to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Jul 6; TLS, 1 p.
    - Thomas Caldecot Chubb to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Aug 9; TLS, 1 p.
    - French translation of excerpt from Jurgen, "Comment l'Empereur Jurgen Passa en Enfer", [1922]; TMs, 4 p.
    - Cyril B. Smith to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Sep 7; ALS, 2 p.
    - John Peale Bishop to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Jun 1; TLS, 1 p.
    - Frank Crowninshield to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Sep 12; TLS, 1 p.
    - Joseph T. Shipley to James Branch Cabell, [1922]; ALS, 1 p.
    - Poem, "Kit Marlowe to Cabell" by Joseph Shipley, [1922]; TMs, 2 p.
    - Beth McCausland to James Branch Cabell, [1922]; ALS, 1 p.
    - Ed Snyder to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Nov 15; TLS, 1 p.
    - Alfred F. Goldsmith to James Branch Cabell, encl. clipping, [1922]; ALS, 1 p.
    - George Keating to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Oct 31; TLS, 1 p.
    - A. L. S. Wood to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Oct 30; TLS, 1 p.
    - Louis Untermeyer to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Oct 19; TLS, 1 p.
    - Robert M. McBride to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Oct 25; TLS, 1 p.
    - Thomas Caldecot Chubb to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Oct 25; TLS, 1 p.
    - Virginia MacFadyen to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Oct 20; ALS, 1 p.
    - H. B. Matthews to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Oct 25; TLS, 1 p.
    - Edgar Jepson to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Oct 22; ALS, 1 p.
    - Sinclair Lewis to James Branch Cabell, [1922] Oct 30; ALS, 2 p.
    - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Nov 15; ALS, 1 p.
    - Isabel Paterson to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Dec 7; TLS, 1 p.
    - F. J. Emmerich to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Dec 12; TLS, 1 p.
    - Benjamin De Casseres to James Branch Cabell, [1922] Dec 6; ALS, 2 p.
    - Harold Ward to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Nov 30; TLS, 1 p.
    - Stanley E. Babb to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Dec 5; TLS, 1 p.
    - Edwin Bjorkman to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Dec 2; ALS, 2 p.
    - Charles J. Dutton to James Branch Cabell, [1922]; TLS, 1 p.
    - Garrard Glenn to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Oct 27; TLS, 2 p.
    - Helen Tooker to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Oct 5; TLS, 2 p.
    - Carl Van Doren to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Oct 24; TLS, 1 p.
    - Ben Ray Redman to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Oct 24; TLS, 2 p.
    - Robert Bell to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Jan 13; TLS, 1 p.
    - A. Burton Clarke to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Jan 24; TLS, 2 p.
    - Emily Grant Hutchings to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Jan 10; TLS, 1 p.
    - Jan Van Male to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Jan 28; TLS, 1 p.
    - Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Jan 15; TLS, 1 p.
    - John Macy to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Jan 15; TLS, 1 p.
    - Ernst Carl Wallau to Robert M. McBride and Co., 1922 Dec 4; TLS, 1 p.
    - Alice E. Stroud to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Jan 19; TLS, 1 p.
    - Byrne [Cobure] to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Sep 7; ALS, 3 p.
    - [ Nell Harrison Powers] to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Jun 1; TLS, 2 p.
    - May L[amberton] Becker to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Jul 16; TLS, 1 p.